San Jose, CA 95124 § 415-867-5241 hungtang@hotmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/hungctang/

Career Objective

An experienced leader with 20+ years of delivering to the customer the best-in-class products and services. I have extensive experience in supporting tier-1 enterprise customers and have launched various hardware and software products, and have engineering program management experience, PLCM, ecosystem and alliance partner management, executive and business development management experience. I seek for opportunities where I can be part of innovative products launches that help to bridge the gaps in people's lives.

Highlights of Expertise

- Program/Project Management
- Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- New Product Introduction Management
- Go-To-Market Strategy & Execution
- Contract Negotiation

- Product Dev & Release Management
- Customer Success & Support Management Strategic Product Planning & Execution
- Business & Channel Partner Development
- OEM/ODM Partner Management

Career Experience

Individual Consultant

Product & Business Development Executive (Aug 2020 - Current)

- Managing N.A. sales and business development effort for Philio Technology
- Advisor to several OEM/ODM manufacturers in smart home product positioning

Alarm.com, Redwood City, CA

Director of Technical Operations & Ecosystem Development (Mar 2017 - Aug 2020)

Led customer success of tier-1 Network Service Providers' end-to-end onboarding and established best practice for rules of engagement with these NSPs. Also served as a Product Management liaison to the Service Provider channel and its IoT GTM strategy at Alarm.com (ADC).

- Led all aspects of customer success and served as a PMO within the sales organization for the NSP accounts
- Program managed NSP accounts onboarding Alarm.com offerings and ongoing release management and product support cadence
- Managed and led regular QBR's with NSP customers to review and share business performance, market trends, strategic roadmaps, and lessons learned
- Advisor to Service Provider partners on IoT GTM strategy (MSOs and Telcos) for various IoT verticals, Home Security/Automation, Wellness/Aging-In-Place, Connected Car, AI, and long-term value prop positioning
- Managed all phases of cloud integration effort between Alarm.com and tier-1 Service Provider's backend support system, i.e. SSO, account creation, system provisioning, etc.

Hung Tang
Page 2

 Led ecosystem development to identifying synergies in both product positioning and GTM strategy across all Service Provider channel customers

- Served as a Product Management liaison for tier-1 Service Providers to help bridge gaps with Alarm.com offerings
- Established and created best practices and rules of engagements working with Tier-1 Service Providers

Icontrol Networks, Redwood City, CA

Director of New Product Programs & Ecosystem Development (May 2011 - Mar 2017)

Managed full end-to-end lifecycles of new products through strategic partner relationships to defining product requirements and integration, and through a Device Development Kit (DDK) framework, across all business units at Icontrol. Developed and managed go-to-market strategy to bringing new Connected Home products into the Icontrol ecosystem across all Business Units (Connect, Converge, and Piper), as well as program manage the end to end integration to product delivery and launch.

- Built and managed ecosystem partner relationships
- A go-to SME not only for smart home device ecosystem partners but also to ADT, Comcast, etc.
- Managed the entire product lifecycle of various products, starting with strategic planning & market research to managing product launches and release cycles
- Maintained product vision through updates and revisions
- Developed product requirements and changes through customer feedback and engineering feasibility study and priority driven timeline
- Jointly developed the end-to-end device development kit integration framework to allow ecosystem partners to implement and certify new products that reduces the effort of a direct integration

Director of Field Operations (Mar 2008 – May 2011)

Program managed Icontrol solution deployment to various Service Provider (ADT, Comcast, Time Warner, and CenturyLink), from evaluation, field trials, to production deployment of Icontrol solution, i.e, residential life-safety and lifestyle CPEs and SAAS (Software as a Service) home security 2.0 web application.

- Program managed all phases of field deployment, from evaluation to field trials to production roll out with two largest cable providers and the largest commercial and residential security providers in US
- Managed inventory planning and strategy with ecosystem partners to meet customer needs
- Owned, documented and managed end-to-end field trials and deployments processes, including an Acceptance Test Plan (ATP), over 100 pages, that the largest cable operator adopted for product acceptance
- Managed key relationships with customers, strategic partners, and internal organization to deliver a worldclass product and service offering to the cable, telco, and security markets
- Worked closely with the executive team to drive and define the product strategy & operations roll-out plan for key customers and partners
- Directed all aspect of deployment readiness from server availability to CPE kitting and provisioning
- Provided guidance to the support organization on best practices to drive bugs to resolution
- Successfully launched iControl product to multiple tier-1 customers, including Xfinity Home Security and ADT Pulse solutions

Hung Tang
Page 3

InnoPath Software, Sunnyvale, CA

Sr. Customer Engineering Manager (2004 - 2008)

Manage a team of senior engineers, including field leads and field operations manager, for both the server and mobile device client aspect of pre-sales support and post-sales support, RFP/RFQ/RFI feedback, field trials, customer demos, internal training, deployment, certification, gap analysis, and system integration.

- Built a worldwide customer engineering deployment & support team across various regions
- Resources & budget management
- Defined best practices Standard Operations Procedure (SOP) for the support organization and for cross functional processes, including project artifact templates development
- Standardized the Service Level Agreement (SLA) template and negotiated SLA to meet both the company and the customer objective
- Drove improvement initiatives to streamline various deployment modeling and RFP/RFQ/RFI responses
- Server support & deployment management, including system integration responsibilities for InnoPath's Over-The-Air (OTA) OMA-DM Carrier solution
- Mobile device Inter-Operability Testing (IOT) support and worked with various OEMs in client porting
- Managed code development and QA'd for change requests in a professional services capacity
- Consultation provided to customer in defining and implementing best practices and geo-redundant solution for disaster recovery
- Owned the end-to-end customer engagement initiatives, from trial to production deployments and all aspects of integration and change requests through SoW efforts
- Served as an escalation point for 24x7 support
- Managed routine QBR's across all customer accounts

Nielsen Mobile (formerly Telephia), San Francisco, CA

Wireless Systems Engineering – Commissioning Manager (2003 - 2004)

Managed a team of commissioning engineers and operators to statistically profile wireless carriers' customer churn, active subscribers versus non-active, using Telephia's dialer technology. Owned commissioning processes and procedures for monthly production commissioning and identifying analytical decision points in the data collected to generate monthly production reports for all wireless carrier customers.

Lightbridge, Irvine CA

Senior Prepaid Product/Deployment Support Engineer (2001 - 2003)

Led Prepaid System deployment, product inter-operability and acceptance testing, and field issue resolution. Served as the SS7 SME within the support/deployment team as well as documented support articles and MRDs. Led and managed CDMA/TDMA/GSM/ WIN II/CAMEL II/IS-41P/IS41EE product Inter-Operability Testing (IOT) initiatives with various mobile switch suppliers (i.e. Motorola, Nortel Networks, etc.).

Hung Tang
Page 4

Nortel Networks, Santa Clara CA

Senior Field Trial Engineer (2000 - 2001)

Managed field trials of long-haul optical switches (1024x1024) as well as customer training and product demos. Served as a subject matter expert at customer site through product incubation and product readiness.

Motorola, Schaumburg IL

Senior Systems Engineer (1998 - 2000)

Technical program management lead to design and deploy a wireless network infrastructure and to provide front line customer support and engineering services from start to finish. Served as a subject matter expert for SMSC deployment, DMS-100 SS7/translation for greenfield customers. Champion to Motorola Harmony Wireless System, a single frame iDEN network for quick and easy deployment, FOA at Incheon International Airport.

Lab Design and Support Systems Engineer (1996 - 1998)

Provided 24x7 engineering services support in a worldwide lab organization within Motorola, consists of multiple wireless networks, analog and CDMA equipment, and served as a webmaster for the department using PERL and HTML for managing lab reservation & remote Terminal/CLI access.

Marketing Systems Engineer (1994 - 1996)

Engineered Subscriber Growth and Frequency Plan proposals for Motorola customers, specifically for network optimization and upgrade recommendations. Wrote and maintained shell scripts and C-code parse tool to manage customer data collected to aid in network optimization proposal and early problem detection.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering | San Francisco State University, San Francisco

Personal Interest

Fishing, Camping, Traveling, Reading, Finances, Emerging Technologies